

LIN KAH KIAT

Negeri Sembilan, Malaysia

(+60) 176279263

kahkiat_94@hotmail.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/kahkiat

linkahkiat.github.io

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

• English, Malay, Chinese

SKILLS SUMMARY

- SECS/GEM protocol
- SCRUM Practice

Programming:

 C#, Python, JavaScript, CSS, MSSQL, Oracle, RestApi, PLC

Others:

Mechanical Design:

• AutoCAD, Catia

Electrical & Electronics Design

Multisim

Machining:

• CNC Machine, Lathe Machine,

EDUCATIONAL:

Bachelor Degree of Engineering (Hons) Mechatronics

Institute : University Malaysia Pahang,

Pekan, Pahang

CGPA : 3.45 / 4.00

Others:

STPM : 2.75 SPM : 7A

CERTIFICATIONS:

- Data Science 360
- Web Development Bootcamp
 (HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node, React)
- Angular 15
- ITIL v4
- Professional Scrum Master™ I (PSM I)

PROFILE

A System Engineer with a passion for integrating devices with systems and driving efficiency. With experience in the Semiconductor and IT industries, I've developed a strong background in manufacturing equipment integration, MES, and Factory Automation. Holding a degree in Mechatronic Engineering, I bring a unique blend of E&E, mechanical, and software skills to the table. Let's connect and explore how I can help drive innovation in your organization.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SENIOR ENGINEER

2.5 YRS (FEB 2023 - NOW)

INFINEON (KULIM) SDN BHD

DEVELOPER (CSC FI EMA INT AP)

~ 1 YRS (SEPT 2024 - NOW)

- Act as a Kulim representative for EAF related topic.
- Joined INT AP team and be developer of EAF Kernel Development Team.
- Work closely with Global Team, continuously developed features and functionality to keep the equipment integrated with the system smoothly. (Eg. Material Start Scenario, Internal trigger Virtual Event, Event Actions, File Connector)
- Provided guidance and support to EMA FE/BE members on using the components of EAF Kernel.
- Enhanced the monitoring idle rule to support ASM tools (non-idle tool), eliminating the need for manual monitoring during server move, increase the team efficiency.

EQUIPMENT INTEGRATOR (CSC FI EMA FE) ~ 1.5 YRS (FEB 2023 - AUG 2024)

- Managed integration and upkeep of 100+ tools in the WET module, ensuring seamless operation and zero critical incidents.
- Led team of 3 and delivered all 20+ WET tools with Equipment Automation Framework (EAF), meeting the WBG project's challenging timeline.
- Successfully migrated a solution to utilize Checktray to read both Carrier and Box ID at same time, replacing the initial barcode scanner approach. Simplify operations to reduce human error.
- Successfully consolidated Equipment Integration (EI) solutions from multiple into a single EI solution, thereby eliminating redundancy.
- Investigated and analyzed log files to identify patterns causing issues.
- Successfully migrated all WET module adaptations from TFS to GIT, achieving the fastest module in the team.
- Awarded 3rd prize in Kulim Green Line Top QRA (Quick Response Action) for enhancing the El solution to avoid human error and prevent wafer scrap.

DEVELOPER

~ 1.5 YRS (SEPT 2021 - JAN 2023)

OTS RETAIL GROUP

- Worked with the company to create REST API designs and develop API systems for their website.
- Pooling data from 10 multi-store database for reporting and analysis.
- Developed an impressive system that helped the company integrate with other third party Accounting Software
- · Automated the data entry process, turn Excel into a database-driven Web Application.

SYSTEM ENGINEER ~ 3 YRS (AUG 2018 - AUG 2021)

CIMATION (M) SDN BHD (SYSTEM INTEGRATOR)

- Designed and implemented a data integration platform that unified production data from PLCs, sensors, IoT devices and improving data visibility.
- Developed a real-time monitoring Dashboard. (e.g. OEE Dashboard)
- Developed multiple web application reports.
- Developed Defects Detect System that integrates robotic arm and machine vision to to automate the inspection process, reducing manual inspection time by 40%.
- Conducted a POC to Tesco Management to demonstrate how a vision system can detect the number of people in queue at each cashier and trigger alert.